Guide to the Larry Palmer papers, 1972-2011.
Palmer, Larry papers, 1972-2011.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Larry Palmer papers, 1972-2011.
18-2-3249
Larry I. Palmer, 1944-
26.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, memoranda, professional writings, and lectures.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, memoranda, professional writings, and lectures concerning Professor Palmer's 27 years at the Cornell Law School, especially his work on the procedure and substance of legal interference in the medical field and issues concerning medical ethics.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor, Cornell Law School, 1975-2002.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, memoranda, professional writings, and lectures concerning Professor Palmer's 27 years at the Cornell Law School, especially his work on the procedure and substance of legal interference in the medical field and issues concerning medical ethics.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Palmer, Larry I., 1944-; Cornell Law School--Faculty.
Subjects:
Medical ethics--United States.; Medical care--United States.; Law--Study and teaching--United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Course Material
Box 1, Folders 1-26
Box 2, Folders 1-26
Boxes 3-5
Box 10, Folder 9
Box 23
Box 29, Folders 8-28
Box 31
Series II. Committees
Box 5
Box 10, Folders 10-11
Box 27
Box 29, Folders 1-6
Box 30, Folders 12-30
Series III. Travel
Box 5
Series IV. Conferences, Seminars, and Institutes
Box 6, Folders 1-25
Box 7, Folders 1-15
Box 10, Folder 8
Box 22
Box 28, Folders 35-40
Box 29, Folder 7
Box 30, Folders 1-11, 31-40
Box 32, Folders 10-65
Box 33
Series V. Publications
Box 7, Folders 16-17
Box 8
Box 10, Folders 14-27
Box 11, Folders 1-15
Box 29, Folders 29-31
Box 32, Folders 6-9
Series VI. Exeter/Harvard - Biographical Info
Box 8
Series VII. Talks and Court Case
Box 9
Series VIII. Research Subject Files
Box 10, Folders 1-13
Boxes 23-27
Box 28, Folders 1-34
Box 32, Folders 1-7
Series IX. Additional Material
Boxes 12-19, 34-38
Series X. Audio Visual Material
Boxes 20, 21
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Course Materials
  - Law and Medicine, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1-25)
  - Law and Medicine, 1982-1998 (Box 2, Folder 1-26)
  - Biology and Society, 1987-1992 (Box 3)
  - Physcian Assisted Suicide Seminar, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - Legislation Course, 1996-2000 (Box 4)
  - Problems in Criminal Justice, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Criminal Law, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Health Law, 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Emerging Problems in Health Care Seminar, Jan. 2000 (Box 4)
  - Overheads for Courses (Box 4)
  - Medical Humanities, Spring 1987 (Box 5)
  - Medical Humanities, Spring 1988 (Box 5)
  - Family Law, 1985-1989 (Box 5)
  - Biology and Society 412 and 426, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Biology and Society 306 -, Spring 1988 (Box 5)
  - Biology and Society 412, Spring 1989 (Box 5)
  - Law: Problem Course in Law and Medicine, Fall 1976 (Box 5)
  - German Medicine - files on Bettina Bauer, German Correspondence and file on the Duty to Save in Germany, Fall 1990 (Box 5)
  - Overheads (Box 5)
  - "Germany Today" Program, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Health Law Class Summaries, Fall 2001 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Course Material, 2003-2004 (Box 23)
  - Student Papers and Presentations (Box 29, Folder 8-20)
  - Georgetown - Miscellaneous (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Georgetown: Urban Public Health Course, Fall 2007 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Public Health Course (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - PHMS 608- Public health Course: Student Papers, 2006 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - PHMS 608: 2nd Paper Assignment (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - PHMS 608: Class Notes, August 2006 (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - PHEH 620: Course Schedule, Spring 2007 (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Scholarship Reading (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - William And Mary School of Law: Course Material, Fall 2007 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Health Law Courses, October 2002 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Student Papers and Presentations, 2007-2008 (Box 31, Folder 3-10)
  - WM Class Notes, Spring 2008 (Box 31, Folder 11-22)
  - Michael Stein's Course, 2008, 2009 (Box 31, Folder 23-24)
  - Legislation Class Notes, Fall 2008 (Box 31, Folder 25-38)
  - Remembering Brown vs. Board, February 2009 (Box 31, Folder 39)
  - Book Orders (Box 31, Folder 40)
  - Course Material: Market Manipulation (Box 31, Folder 41)
  - Course Material: SARS; Reproductive Health (Box 31, Folder 42)
  - Course Material: Obesity, Wieght Bias, Health Irregularities (Box 31, Folder 43)
  - Problems in Health Law Policy Course Syllabus, Spring 2009 (Box 31, Folder 44)
  - Course Material: Health policy, January 2009 (Box 31, Folder 45)
  - Course Material: Patient Safety (Box 31, Folder 46-48)
  - Course Material: Brief of Supreme Court - Heller vs. DC (Box 31, Folder 49-50)
  - Course Material, Notes, Student Papers: Health Care Politics and Policy, Fall 2009 (Box 31, Folder 51-52)
  - Class Notes: Seminar on Problems in Health Law and Policy, Spring 2009 (Box 34, Folder 33-46)
  - Course Material, Class 1-28: Seminar on Problems in Health Law and Policy, Fall 2009 (Box 35, Folder 1-27)
  - Health Law and Policy Exam Outlines, Fall 2009 (Box 35, Folder 28-29, 34)
  - Health Law and Policy Exam Outlines, Fall 2010 (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - Health Care Politics and Policy Exam Outlines, Fall 2009 (Box 35, Folder 33)
  - Health Care Politics and Policy Final Exam Outline (* Student Exams REMOVED), Fall 2009 (Box 35, Folder 36, 39-41)
  - Health Care Politics and Policy: Death and Dying Problem, Fall 2009 (Box 35, Folder 38)
  - Health Care Politics and Policy Group Papers--* REMOVED, September 22, 2009 (Box 35, Folder 42)
  - Health Care Politics and Policy Classes 1-26 Notes, Spring 2010 (Box 35, Folder 44-70)
  - Bioethics, Medical Ethics, and the Law: Class Articles, Spring 2010 (Box 35, Folder 71)
  - Bioethics, Medical Ethics, and the Law Exam Question Outlines (*Student Exams REMOVED), Spring 2010 (Box 35, Folder 72-75)
  - Health Care Law and Bioethics Lecture Notes and Assignments, July 2010 (Box 35, Folder 80-85, 88-89)
  - Health Care Law and Policy Lecture Slides, Fall 2010 (Box 35, Folder 90-98)
  - Health Care Law and Policy Class 10-24 Notes and Assignments, Syllabus, Midterm, Fall 2010, Fall 2009 (Box 36, Folder 1-19, 24-25)
  - Health Care Law and Policy Final Exam, Fall 2010 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Health Care Law and Policy Notes and Exams, Spring 2011 (Box 36, Folder 26-31)
  - Bioethics, Medical Ethics and Law Classes 1-28 Notes and Course Material, Spring 2011 (Box 36, Folder 32-59, 65-67)
  - Bioethics, Medical Ethics and Law Exams and Review, Spring 2011 (Box 36, Folder 60-64)
  - Emerging Problems: Urban Public Health Course Pack, Spring 2008 (Box 36, Folder 68-70)
  - Health Care Law and Bioethics Course Syllabus, Answer Sheets, Review Sheets, Spring 2011 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Health Care Law and Bioethics Lecture Notes, Fall 2010 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Health Care Law and Bioethics Final Exam/Midterm, Fall 2010 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Health Care Law and Bioethics Class 3-9, Spring 2011 (Box 37, Folder 7-11)
  - Bioethics, Medical Ethics, and the Law Exam and Course Review, Spring 2011 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Health Care Law and Bioethics Chapter Notes, Sept 13-19 2010 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Health Law and Policy Class 7-9 Notes, Fall 2010 (Box 37, Folder 15-17)
  - Seminar on Problems in Health Law and Policy Course Information, Spring 2009 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Legislation Exam Questions, Fall 2008 (Box 37, Folder 21-23)
  - Health Law and Policy Exams and Outlines, Fall 2010 (Box 37, Folder 24-28)
  - Emerging Problems in Urban Public Health Course Materials, Fall 2007 (Box 37, Folder 29-34)
- Series II. Committees
  - LIP - Housing Advisory Committee, 1988 (Box 5)
  - LIP - CSPE Committee, Jun-86 (Box 5)
  - LIP - CSPE Steering Committee, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Middle States Visiting Team - Reaccreditation of Princeton, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Residential Learning House at Cornell, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
  - Ethics Committee, 2003-2004 (Box 27)
  - Hastings Center Meetings, 2006 (Box 27)
  - Proposal to Create the Center for Health Policy and Law, May 2009 (Box 29, Folder 1-5)
  - VCU - WH Sample Agreement (Rice Center), January 2009 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Meetings, Conferences, Reports: NIH National Advisory Council on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism, 2007-2009 (Box 30, Folder 12-20)
  - Meetings, Conferences, Reports: The Hastings Center, 2006-2009 (Box 30, Folder 21-30)
- Series III. Travel
  - Travel for Research, Pre - 1980 (Box 5)
  - Nashville Conference on Health Planning, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - Champaign, Univ. of Illinois, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - San Diego, Cornell Club, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Hong Kong - foreign exchanges, 1988-1989 (Box 5)
  - Atlanta, Emory University, 1988-1989 (Box 5)
  - Germany and Paris, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
  - London - Conference on Health Law and Ethics, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
  - South Africa - cancelled, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
  - Research Travel, 1990-1991 (Box 5)
  - Paris, 1992 (Box 5)
- Series IV. Conferences, Seminars, and Institutes
  - National Minority Conference on Human Experimentation - VA., 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
  - Human Experimentation - Larry Palmer, 1973 & 1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Articles, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Technology Assessment Project Program on Science, Technology and Socity - at Cornell - Kurt Hanslowe's paper (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Summer Institute for the Study of Problems of Children and the Law, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 9-13)
  - Children and the Law - Larry Palmer, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - State Law Enforcement Planning Agency of NJ - A Decisional Model for Criminal Dispositions - Final Report - Larry Palmer - Project Director, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Materials on Problems of Sentences - Larry Palmer, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 16-19)
  - Sentencing Seminar - Spring Semester, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 20-23)
  - "A Modeling of Criminal Dispoisitions: An Alternative to Official Discretion in Sentencing" - Larry Palmer (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence concerning "A Model of Criminal Dispositions", 1973 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Summer Institute on Econmics for Law Professors - Rochester, NY., 1973 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Summer Institute Materials, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 2-4)
  - Aids and Society - Articles, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5-12)
  - Managed Care Seminar, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 13-15)
  - Strategic Thinking Retreat, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Conferences and talks given in 2005, 2005 (Box 22)
  - Medical Society of Virginia, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - Community Campus Partnership for Health, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - National Jeane Priesk Extension Health Conference, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - ABA Conference, Orlando, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - HRPP Conference, Washington, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - The Hastings Center, 2007-2008 (Box 28, Folder 40)
  - University of Virginia Talk, June 2007 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Hofstra University Conference: New Directions in American Health Care, March 2010 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - University of Texas Health Center Conference: Cardiovascular Research, May 2007 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Phillips Exeter Academy, May 2008 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - CADRE Conference, 2002, 2005, 2007 (Box 30, Folder 4-6)
  - CADRE Presentation, Tucson, May 2008 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - American Lung Association, 2008 (Box 30, Folder 8-9)
  - American Lung Association: Leadership Board Resource Manual (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Planned Parenthood: Louisville, August 2006 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Citizen Lawyer Conference, February 2008 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Military Medical Ethics Workshop, September 2008 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - HPLI Presentation, January 2008 (Box 30, Folder 33)
  - Louisville Metro Health Development Programme: Policy Development Training, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 34-40)
  - HPLI: Mission and Vision (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - HPLI: Future Projects (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - HPLI: Press Conference, May 2008 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - HPLI Speaker Series, 2009 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - HPLI: Working Group Meetings, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 14-18)
  - HPLI: Presentations and Talks, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 19-20)
  - HPLI: Phoenix Project (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - HPLI: Staff and Advisory Board (Box 32, Folder 22-25)
  - HPLI: Peer Institutions (Box 32, Folder 26-28)
  - HPLI: Community Partners, 2006 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - HPLI: Clinics (Box 32, Folder 30-32)
  - William and Mary Law School: Legal Skills (Box 32, Folder 33)
  - VCU: Health Justice and Communications Initiative, July 2007 (Box 32, Folder 34)
  - VCU: 6th Annual Social Equity University Conference, February 2007 (Box 32, Folder 35)
  - William and Mary Law School: Faculty (Box 32, Folder 36)
  - VCU: School of Pharmacy (Box 32, Folder 37-38)
  - VCU: Department of African American Studies (Box 32, Folder 39)
  - VCU: Meetings with Sheldon Retchin (Box 32, Folder 40-41)
  - VCU: Meetings with SAM and Dean Holsworth, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 42)
  - VCU: Carlos Aranciba, Donald Tortonica, sTEVE gRAVELY, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 43)
  - VCU: Peer Institutions, 2007 (Box 32, Folder 44)
  - VCU: Miscellaneous Documents, Summer 2008 (Box 32, Folder 45)
  - VCU: Enrichment Award Letter, 2009 (Box 32, Folder 46)
  - VCU: School of Medicine Strategic Plan 2005-2011, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 47)
  - William and Mary Law School: Patricia Roberts, 2007 (Box 32, Folder 48)
  - VCU: Center for Human Needs (Box 32, Folder 49-50)
  - VCU: Center for Health Disparity (Box 32, Folder 51)
  - VCU: Department of Epidemiology and Community Health, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 52-53)
  - VCU: Don Gehring, Karen Radar, Martin Lenhardt, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 54)
  - VCU: PonJala Coney, Dean of Faculty Affairs, October 2007 (Box 32, Folder 55)
  - VCU and William and Mary School Schedule, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 56)
  - VCU: Organizational Charts (Box 32, Folder 57)
  - VCU: Board of Visitors, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 58)
  - VCU: 2020 Vision of Excellence (Box 32, Folder 59)
  - VCU: Department of Social and Behavioral Health, September 2007 (Box 32, Folder 60)
  - VCU: Roice Luke (Box 32, Folder 61)
  - VCU: Grace Harris Leadership Institute, September 2008 (Box 32, Folder 62)
  - VCU: Wilder School, 2007 (Box 32, Folder 63-65)
  - Virginia Healthcare Foundation, May 2008 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - The Hastings Center: Erika Blacksher (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Schroeder Center for Healthcare Policy, June 2007 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Collaborating Center for Professional Education in Public Health Law (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - International Hospital for Children, 2007 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Union Theological Seminary and Presbyterian School of Christian Education (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Ashoka's Global Academy: Social Enterprise Series (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Address: "Cornell: Marrying Science, Artistry, the humanities and Professional Practice" (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Veterans Benefit Clinic, "When Duty Calls" Appendices, 2008 (Box 33, Folder 9-10)
  - Veterans Benefit Clinic: Articles and Research (Box 33, Folder 11-13)
  - Veterans Benefit Clinic: Grant, 2008 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Veterans Benefit Clinic: LCS Meeting, August 2008 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Veterans Benefit Clinic: CPSD, 2008 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Veterans Benefit Clinic: Richmond "VA" Projects, 2008 (Box 33, Folder 17)
- Series V. Publications
  - Notes on Speedy Dispositions of Appeals, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - "Implementing the Obligation of Advocacy in Review of Criminal Convictions" - L. Palmer, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Policy Choices in Mandatory Sentencing - L. Palmer, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Reviews of "Policy Choices in Mandatory Sentences", 1977 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - "Adoption: A Plea for Realistic Consitutional Adjudication" - L. Palmer, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - "The Role of Appellate Courts in Mandatory Sentencing Schemes" - L. Palmer, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - "Positions of Justices Stewart and White on the Death Penalty: A Study of Two Perspectives on Structuring Discretion" - L. Palmer, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - "Law, Medicine and Social Justice " - L. Palmer, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 23-26)
  - Article in Cornell Journal of Law and Public Policy - "Institutional Analysis and Physicians" Rights After Vacco V. Quill" - L. Palmer, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - The Nature of Liberal and Professional Undergraduate Education at Cornell - intro by L. Palmer, 1989 (Box 7)
  - Report of the Provost's Commission on Writing, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Review of Minority Education at Cornell Univesity, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Replies to the Draft Report of the Subcommittee on Minority Education, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Science and Mathematics Education - Programs and Proceedings, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence and material collected for writing the books Law, Medicine and Social Justice, published in 1989 and Endings and Beginnings: Medicine and Law in Assisted Life and Death, published in 2000. (Box 8)
  - Tuskegee - Henry Foster - Study Guide, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Medical Ethics - "Confronting Medical Ethics" - L. Palmer, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Medical Ethics - "Ethical - Diabetes Self Management - L. Palmer, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Medical Ethics -"High Priests Questioned or At Least. - L. Palmer, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Medical Ethics -"Mandatory Testing for Aids" panel - L. Palmer, Nov. 1977 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Medical Ethics - "Does Christ Fit?" - L. Palmer (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Medical Ethics - Uncertainty in Prof. Practice - L. Palmer, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Medical Ethics - "Attorney Liability for Malpr.", 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Medical Ethics - Conf: Health Law and Ethics, London - L. Palmer - includes Conf. Program (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Medical Ethics - "Research Paradigm for Teaching" - L. Palmer, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Medical Ethics - ""Understanding Medical Malpractice Practice" - L. Palmer, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Criminal Law - "Death Penalty" - teaching notes - L. Palmer, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Criminal Law - "Euthanasia and Suicide" teaching note - L. Palmer, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Family Law - "Choice for Women Only" - L. Palmer, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Family Law - "Comment on .. Katkin, Bullington.." - L. Palmer (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Family Law - "Family Dissolution and the Law" - L. Palmer, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Family Law - "No Rights for Sperm Donors" - L. Palmer, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Family Law - "Reproductive Choices and the Law" - L. Palmer, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Family Law - "Role of Guardians in Surrogacy Lit. - L. Palmer, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Family Law - "Surrogacy and the Right to Counsel" - L. Palmer, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Family Law - "Surrogacy & Other Technologies" - L. Palmer, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Fetal Alcohol Syndrome - "The Ethical and Legal Implications" - L. Palmer (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Frozen Embryos - "Fr. Embryos, the Law & Med. Ethics" - L. Palmer (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Law and Medicine - Conf. - Health Law Teachers, Boston (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Law and Medicine - "Law/Medicine: The Right to Live" - L. Palmer (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Law and Medicine - "How to Decide When Death Comes" - L. Palmer (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Law and Medicine - "Law and Medicine at a Crossroads" - L. Palmer (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Law and Medicine - Quinlan Case and the Right to Die Symposium, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Honors Thesis - "Fetal Tissue Transplantation Research Policy: An Analysis of Problem Characterizations, Political Conflict, and Organizational Differences- by Christopher Tedeschi, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Honors Thesis - "Medical Malpractice Reform in NY and Florida" - by Aashish Gandhi, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Articles (Box 17, Folder 25-30)
  - Fetal Alcohol Syndrome Paper Drafts, Commentary, French and English - Larry Palmer, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 1, 7)
  - "Towards and Multicultural University" - L. Palmer, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Institutional Analysis and Physicians Rights after Vacco v. Quill - L Palmer, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Reprints "No Rights for Sperm Donors" - L. Palmer, 1988-1989 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Preface, Conference on German Medicine, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - "A Choice for Women Only" - L Palmer, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - "Confronting Medical Ethics" - L Palmer, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Ethical and Legal Implications of Diabetes Self-Management"- L Palmer, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - "How to Decide When Death Comes" - L Palmer, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - "Research with Human Subjects as a Paradigm in Teaching" - L Palmer (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - "Understanding the Medical Malpractice Crisis" - L Palmer, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - "The Legal Significance of Gestation" - L Palmer, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Assorted Publications - L. Palmer (Box 29, Folder 29-31)
  - "Can Laws Make Us Healthy?" - A. Desoff, 2007 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Assorted Publications - J. Twigg, 2009 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - ERISA Preemption Doctrine as Health policy (Draft) - L. Palmer, 2010 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - "Allies not Adversaries: Teaching Collaboration..." - E. Tyler (Box 32, Folder 9A)
  - NIAAA Journals, 2006-2008 (Box 32, Folder 9B)
  - Medical Research Law and Policy Report, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 9C)
  - Miscellaneous Journals, 2008 (Box 32, Folder 9D)
  - "Access to Health Care: What Level of Reform?" - L. Palmer, 2007 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - "Checkerboard Segregation in the 1950's"- Larry Palmer, 2008 (Box 36, Folder 21)
- Series VI. Exeter/Harvard - Biographical material
  - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 8)
  - Bateman Controversy, 1993 (Box 8)
  - John Phillips Award Committee, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Long-Range Planning Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 8)
  - Nominating Committee, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Trustees Orientation Committee, 1990s (Box 8)
  - Mailing lists and Stationery, 1990s (Box 8)
  - Harvard's 350th Anniversary, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Photographs (Box 8)
  - Biographical piece, 1993 (Box 8)
- Series VII. Talks and Court Case
  - Titles for each talk are on each folder, 1986-1994 (Box 9, Folder 1-54)
  - Court Case - Tompkins County - Eugene Duncan- Volumes I-V, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 55-69)
- Series VIII. Research Subject Files
  - Royal Commission Publications, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Aids, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Bhopal, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Family Law, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Family Law - Baby M/Surrogacy, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Guardianship, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Malpractice, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Samples - Interviews done by L. Palmer - Questions prepared under the guidance of the Children's Defense Fund, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
  - Sickle Cell Disease, 2003-2004 (Box 23)
  - End of Life Issues, 2003-2004 (Box 23)
  - End of Life Issues, 2004-2005 (Box 24)
  - Asthma, 2004-2005 (Box 24)
  - Uninsured, 2004-2005 (Box 25)
  - Healthcare Reform, 2004-2005 (Box 25)
  - Sickle Cell Disease, 2005-2006 (Box 26)
  - Center for Environmental Systems Biology, 2005-2006 (Box 26)
  - Obesity, 2004 (Box 27)
  - Air Quality Task Force, 2004 (Box 27)
  - Patient Safety Proposed Regulations, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Politics of Public Health (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Veteran Affairs - HSR & D (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Bioethics of Disability, 2007 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Politics, Ethics and Legality Research, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - System Science Health Policy, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Research Involving Prisoners, 2005-2006 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Massachusetts Health Reform, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Health Policy Research, 2007 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Organizational Ethics, 2002-2004 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Change in Public Health: Of Rights and Commodities, 2007 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Robert Wood Johnson Policy Grant, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Epidemiology/Community Health (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - A Cultural Evaluation of Sunstein on Risk, 2005-2006 (Box 28, Folder 14)